Will O'Neill

Writer, Narrative Designer and Game Developer

706-410 Queens Quay W. Toronto, ON M5V 3T1, Canada (647) 206-7504

will.oneill@outlook.com willoneill.com/portfolio

EXPERIENCE

Fire Hose Games, Boston — Writer & Narrative Designer

2022 - 2024

Writing and narrative development on Techtonica, as well as trailer writing, voiceover direction, casting and localization production.

WZO Games Inc., Toronto — Founder

2013 - PRESENT

Creator of the critically acclaimed narrative-focused games Actual Sunlight, Little Red Lie and F2P mobile game Guildmaster Story.

Multiple Studios, Worldwide — Writer & Narrative Designer

2013 - PRESENT

Writing and narrative development on SUPERLIMINAL, You Will Die Here Tonight and others. Visit <u>willoneill.com/portfolio</u> to learn more.

EDUCATION

University of Toronto, Toronto — Bachelor of Arts

English and Philosophy

Centennial College, Toronto — Postgraduate Certificate

Public Relations & Corporate Communications

TRAINING

Complete Unity Game Developer - Udemy

Unreal Engine Blueprint Game Developer – *Udemy*

Complete Godot 2D - Udemy

HIGHLIGHTS

11,000+ Reviews on Steam

10+ games shipped on multiple platforms - Steam, PS4, PS Vita, Xbox, iOS and Android - including three self-published on PC and PlayStation consoles

8+ years of experience in games writing, 10+ in corporate communications and copywriting

SKILLS

Engines: Unity, RPG Maker, Adventure Game Studio (AGS), Ren'py

Narrative Tools: Articy Draft, Arcweave, Adventure Creator, Dialogue System

Voiceover Direction: Remote and in-studio, extensive across game and corporate clients

Production: Affinity Photo / Designer, Adobe Photoshop / Illustrator, Logic Pro, Audacity, Shotcut, FCP

Publishing: Managed Steam and console submissions - TRC process, ratings, store submissions, etc.